<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Stou.dk</title>
      <generator uri="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://stou.dk/tags/software/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Rasmus Stougaard</author>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2003 - 2014, Rasmus Stougaard; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <updated>Sun, 23 Nov 2014 20:42:55 &#43;0800</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Travel Blogging Setup</title>
      <link>http://stou.dk/2014/11/travel-blogging-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2014 20:42:55 &#43;0800</pubDate>
      <author>Rasmus Stougaard</author>
      <guid>http://stou.dk/2014/11/travel-blogging-setup/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;/media/2014/travel-blogging-setup/blogging-theme-cover-01.png&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I am currently travelling with my family in South East asia.
The trip is planned to last about one year, so before we left home (Denmark) I set up a blog to
use as a diary for ourselves and to keep friends and family updated while we are away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I like to do a little programming in my spare time, I decided to use &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.com&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; as my blogging platform.
That has been a wise choice so far, and I can only recommend that you give it a try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most places we have stayed, the internet connection has not exactly been very reliable nor fast.
A few exeptions were some guest houses in Vietnam, which to my surprise had very decent connections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;benefits-of-using-hugo-for-me:4ee05812e701e9e8226f56e87ffea6bc&#34;&gt;Benefits of using Hugo for Me&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Completely self contained offline editing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edit content using Markdown (even my wife can do this).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easy deployment using github pages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No worries about servers, databases, backups etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;creating-a-theme:4ee05812e701e9e8226f56e87ffea6bc&#34;&gt;Creating a Theme&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to experiment with creating my own theme for the site, to get at better feel of how hugo works.
Of course this took a litle trial and error, but wasn&amp;rsquo;t too hard given the &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io/themes/creation/&#34;&gt;documentation of Hugo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hugo-documentation-offline:4ee05812e701e9e8226f56e87ffea6bc&#34;&gt;Hugo documentation offline&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need to work offline, do yourself a favour and clone the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/spf13/hugo&#34;&gt;hugo git repo&lt;/a&gt;. Then you can serve up the hugo docs locally like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd path/to/hugo
cd docs
hugo server -p 1314
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that i am serving the docs on a different port, since i lets me use the default port (1313) for the blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having a copy of the hugo git repo also lets you compile the hugo binary from the sources, and maybe contribute to the project and help improve the platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;foundation-tweaks:4ee05812e701e9e8226f56e87ffea6bc&#34;&gt;Foundation Tweaks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I chose to give &lt;a href=&#34;http://foundation.zurb.com&#34;&gt;Foundation&lt;/a&gt; a try, and I wanted to use the Sass version.
However, the default project created by foundation, doesn&amp;rsquo;t play nice with the folder layout used by hugo so I had to tweak the configuration a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically I created a default Foundation project, and modified the paths to generate the bower components, and the compiled css inside the &lt;code&gt;static&lt;/code&gt; folder used by hugo.
The sass sources (scss folder) was not moved into the &lt;code&gt;static&lt;/code&gt; folder, since the generated site only uses the compiled css file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I editing the theme, I keep two terminals open. One running &lt;code&gt;bundle exec compass watch&lt;/code&gt; to update the css when the sass input changes, and another terminal running &lt;code&gt;hugo server -w&lt;/code&gt; to serve up the site locally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I gain from this is the ability to work with the theme styles using sass pre-processing, and still leverage the power of liveupdating the site provided by hugo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;get-the-source:4ee05812e701e9e8226f56e87ffea6bc&#34;&gt;Get the Source&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to take a closer look at the details, I have published &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/stou/stou-dk-theme&#34;&gt;my theme on github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;/media/2014/motack-n-malls/IMG_7206.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Enjoying the freedom of open source&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
